

# JAROSLAV KOTRBA



+420 604 724 303





Czech Republic, Brno



https://jaroslavkotrba.com

# **SKILLS**

- R (Data tables, Shiny)
- Python (Pandas, PySpark, Plotly, Scikit-learn, Statsmodels, LangChain)
- SQL (T-SQL, MySQL)
- Git (GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira)
- Google Cloud (APIs)

# **LANGUAGES**

- CZECH (Native speaker)
- GERMAN (C1 certification)
- ENGLISH (C1 certification)
- FRENCH (A2)

# HOBBIES

- Calisthenics (body-weight training)
- Interactive web applications
- Reading (also audiobooks)

# *SUMMARY*

With four years of experience as a data analyst and risk software developer, I possess a comprehensive understanding of building data pipelines for risk metrics calculation, machine learning models, and database management. I have extensive experience leveraging tools such as R, Python, SQL, and advanced data analytics techniques to drive business insights.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Risk Software Developer & Analyst**

#### **Barclays**

Oct 2022 - Present

#### Remote

- Credit risk metrics calculation and capital regulatory reporting
- Basel IV Securitization, RWA and EAD calculation with PD and LGD
- Creating data pipelines for internal rsageICOM model
- Developing and updating SQL databases
- Communication of requirements with users and business analysts

# **EMEA Mobility Leader & Data Analyst**

#### Honeywell

Jan 2022 - Sep 2022

#### Brno

- Leading Mobility services operations within EMEA region
- Detailed Cost Analysis and Cost Optimizations in R & Python
- People leader (Line Manager) of EMEA Mobility Team
- Responsible for new contract implementation projects
- Process creation, maintaining, and improvement

## **Data Analyst**

#### Honeywell

Jun 2020 - Dec 2021

- Billing reports automation and optimization in R and Python
- Clustering and modeling of usage data across EMEA
- Forecasting of aircraft deliveries and retirement
- Risk evaluation of new mobility contracts
- · Database cleaning and maintaining

# EDUCATION

#### Masaryk University

#### **Economic Policy and International Relations**

2017-2020

- Econometrics
- Big Data with SQL
- Calculation Systems in Statistics
- Statistics for Computer Science

### **English Linguistics, Literature and History** 2016-2019

• Semantics with focus on translation

#### German Linguistics, Literature and History 2013-2017

Corpus linguistics



